{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Zimbabwe","Finland"],"question":"Which country is associated with the cocktail Mojito?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Communist Manifesto","incorrectAnswers":["The American Declaration of Independence","The Gettysberg Address","Magna Carta"],"question":"The last line of which document is 'Working men of all countries, unite.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","San Marino","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Grand Theft Auto","incorrectAnswers":["Gear to Advance","Grind Them All!","Go to America"],"question":"Which video game series is sometimes referred to as GTA?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Daft Punk","incorrectAnswers":["Gong","Indochine","Nouvelle Vague"],"question":"Which French electronica duo released the studio album 'Random Access Memories'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Brass","Stringed"],"question":"What type of instrument is a cowbell?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mimosa","incorrectAnswers":["Daiquiri","Cosmopolitan","Margarita"],"question":"What is the name of the orange juice and champagne cocktail often drank at breakfast?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used for surface purification, bleaching, odour removal and water disinfection.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used as an ingredient in the production of glass, bricks, and ceramics.","It is used to manufacture dry wall.","It is used to relieve pain and inflammation."],"question":"What is the chemical sodium hypochlorite often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Jumpin', Jumpin'\" by Destiny's Child","incorrectAnswers":["\"A Thousand Miles\" by Vanessa Carlton","\"Baby Got Back\" by Sir Mix-a-Lot","\"Hurt\" by Nine Inch Nails"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Ladies leave your man at home, the club is full of ballers and their pockets full grown.\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","Africa","Autralasia"],"question":"In which continent would you find the Ob river?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Boar","incorrectAnswers":["A Tiercel","A Ram","A Jack"],"question":"What is the word for a male hedgehog?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used to manufacture dry wall.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used in thermometers, thermostats, barometers","It is used in laundry detergent.","It is used to relieve pain."],"question":"What is the chemical calcium sulphate dihydrate often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Bulgaria","Germany","Hungary"],"question":"Warsaw is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Greg Norman","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Nicklaus","Rory McIlroy","Gary Player"],"question":"Who Did Tiger Woods Replace As The World's Number One Ranked Golfer In 1998?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Robert Jordan","incorrectAnswers":["Suzanne Collins","Jack Vance","Donna Leon"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Wheel of Time'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"EMF","incorrectAnswers":["Deee-Lite","Andrea True Connection","Musical Youth"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1991 with Unbelievable?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Herpetologist","incorrectAnswers":["Entomologist","Barologist","Seismologist"],"question":"What is a scientist who studies reptiles and amphibians known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jane Seymour","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Boleyn","Catherine Parr","Catherine Howard"],"question":"Who Was The 3rd Wife Of Henry VIII?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Antonin Dvorak","incorrectAnswers":["Ludwig van Beethoven","Johann Sebastian Bach","Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart"],"question":"Who headed New York City's National Conservatory of Music from 1892 to 1895, but returned to Bohemia due to homesickness?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Gupta Empire","incorrectAnswers":["Ming Empire","Siamese Empire","Khmer Empire"],"question":"Which of these was an empire on the Indian subcontinent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Naive art","incorrectAnswers":["Beginner's art","Natural art","Pop art"],"question":"Name the art style, usually paintings, characterized by a simplified style, nonscientific perspective, and bold colors. The artists are generally not professionally trained.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Beirut","incorrectAnswers":["Male","Basseterre","Nassau"],"question":"What is the capital city of Lebanon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dr Who","incorrectAnswers":["Star Trek","Battlestar Galactica","The Twilight Zone"],"question":"Which long running sci-fi program was first aired in November 1963?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belize","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Nicaragua","Panama"],"question":"Which Central American country extends furthest north?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The A.B.C. Murders","incorrectAnswers":["The Murder of Roger Ackroyd","Lolita","The Name of the Rose"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'It was in June of 1935 that I came home from my ranch in South America for a stay of about six months.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Procter & Gamble","incorrectAnswers":["Ben & Jerry's","Marks & Spencer","Coca-Cola"],"question":"Which company, named after its two founders,  sells everything from Charmin to Duracell?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The California Gold Rush","incorrectAnswers":["The American Civil War","The Cuban Revolution","The Louisiana Purchase"],"question":"What started in 1849 when gold was discovered at Sutter's Mill?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Shirley Bassey","incorrectAnswers":["Lulu","Wings","Billie Eilish"],"question":"Who performed the theme song to the James Bond film Moonraker?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Otto Hahn","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Wilhelm Rontgen","Mervin Glick"],"question":"Which German Chemist Won The Nobel Prize For Chemistry In 1944 For Discovering Nuclear Fission?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Immanuel Kant","incorrectAnswers":["Baruch Spinoza","Martin Heidegger","Bertrand Russell"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Metaphysics is a dark ocean without shores or lighthouse, strewn with many a philosophic wreck'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Four","incorrectAnswers":["One","Five","Three"],"question":"In German, what is the meaning of the word 'vier'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Three","incorrectAnswers":["Four","Five","Six"],"question":"How many astronauts manned each Apollo flight?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Lee Harvey Oswald","incorrectAnswers":["John Wilkes Booth","Gerald Ford","Mark David Chapman"],"question":"Who assassinated president Kennedy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["Sweden","Estonia","Iceland"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Brussels?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Milwaukee Brewers","incorrectAnswers":["Milwaukee Jets","Milwaukee Orioles","Milwaukee Tigers"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Milwaukee?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the song 'Alejandro'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Common-law","incorrectAnswers":["Civil","Religious","Arranged"],"question":"What is another name for an informal marriage that often comes with some level of legal recognition?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"mollusks","incorrectAnswers":["the Earth","dialects","religion"],"question":"What is Malacology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Lesotho","Eswatini","Angola"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Botswana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Keira Knightley","incorrectAnswers":["Laura Linney","Sarah Paulson","Melissa Leo"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Atonement and Love Actually?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Crane","incorrectAnswers":["Butterfly","Moose","Crocodile"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Japan Airlines logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Elephant","incorrectAnswers":["Lion","Rhino","Donkey"],"question":"Which animal is the symbol of the U.S. Republican Party?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jane Foster","incorrectAnswers":["Gamora","Thena","Agent Maria Hill"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Natalie Portman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Ronnie O'Sullivan","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Selby","Judd Trump","John Higgins"],"question":"Who won the 2022 Snooker World Championship?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Okara","incorrectAnswers":["Soy milk","Miso Soup","Nattō"],"question":"What is the name of the pulpy leftover when tofu is made from soybeans?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Posset ","incorrectAnswers":["Hot Toddie","Yarg","Bitter Buttie"],"question":"Which drink made of hot milk curdled with ale, wine, etc. and often flavoured with spices, was formerly used as a cold remedy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Robbins","incorrectAnswers":["Tim Roth","Hugo Weaving","Timothy Spall"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both The Shawshank Redemption and Top Gun?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sedimentary Rocks","incorrectAnswers":["Igneous Rocks","Metamorphic Rocks","Fossils"],"question":"What type of rock is formed by the compaction and cementation of particles and organic material?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Great Britain","incorrectAnswers":["Prussia","Russia","Austria"],"question":"Which country declared war on France first in the Napoleonic wars?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joaquin Phoenix","incorrectAnswers":["Antonio Banderas","Leonardo DiCaprio","Adam Driver"],"question":"Who won the 2019 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Arthur Fleck in Joker?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Marjoram","incorrectAnswers":["Thyme","Basil","Mint"],"question":"What herb is oregano most closely related to?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"4","incorrectAnswers":["2","3","1"],"question":"How Many Chambers Are There In Your Heart?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the studio album 'A Head Full of Dreams'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"July 4th, 1776","incorrectAnswers":["July 5th, 1801","July 4th, 1801","July 5th, 1776"],"question":"On what date did America become an independant nation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Philip II","incorrectAnswers":["Carlos I","Ferdinand III","Charles IV"],"question":"Which Spanish King sent an armada against England in 1588","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"NBC","incorrectAnswers":["Slazenger","Porsche","ING Group"],"question":"Which of these brands has a peacock on its logo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Who released the song 'Run the World'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sodom and Gomorrah","incorrectAnswers":["Jericho and Babylon","Pain and Pity","Avarice and Jealousy"],"question":"What two biblical cities did God destroy with fire and brimstone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Democritus","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Denis Diderot","Jean-Paul Sartre"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The brave man is he who overcomes not only his enemies but his pleasures'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Spain ","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","France","Russia"],"question":"From which country does the dish paella originate?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Billy Bob Thornton","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Seth Rogen","John Turturro"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including Armageddon and Love Actually?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Sahara ","incorrectAnswers":["The Gobi","The Mojave","The Arabian"],"question":"What Is The Worlds Largest Hot Desert?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roadrunner","incorrectAnswers":["Emu","Bald Eagle","Canary"],"question":"Which Bird Is Resident Of The American Southwest & Has Been Immortilized In A Cartoon Series?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Capricorn","incorrectAnswers":["Gemini","Aries","Scorpio"],"question":"If you were born on Christmas Day, what would your star sign be?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"New Coke","incorrectAnswers":["Aqua Cola","Dasani","Orange Cola"],"question":"What mistake did Coca-Cola make in 1985?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oslo","incorrectAnswers":["Lyon","Cologne","Munich"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Norway?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pacific","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantic","Indian","Arctic"],"question":"What ocean was amelia earhart flying over when she disappeared","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Linkin Park","incorrectAnswers":["Alice in Chains","Hollywood Undead","System of a Down"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Living Things'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"The iconic song 'Vogue' was a hit by which musician?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hartford","incorrectAnswers":["Belford","Scranton","Bellaclaire"],"question":"What U.S city is known as Insurance City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Franz Kafka","incorrectAnswers":["Émile Zola","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Leo Tolstoy"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Castle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Germany","France"],"question":"Nicolaus Copernicus, famous for his theory that the sun was at the center of the solar system, was born in which country in 1473?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Tibet","incorrectAnswers":["Bhutan","Nepal","Mongolia"],"question":"Which country did China invade on Christmas day 1950","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Minimalism","incorrectAnswers":["Simplicism","Aesthetics","Surrealism"],"question":"Which art movement emphasized pure, reduced forms and strict, systematic composition?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"One","incorrectAnswers":["Two","Three","Four"],"question":"How many referees work a soccer game?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"10","incorrectAnswers":["6","8","12"],"question":"What is the value of the letter Q in Scrabble?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A young man joins forces with an old man, a cocky pilot, a beast and two robots to save the galaxy.","incorrectAnswers":["The son of a city's mastermind falls in love with a working-class prophet.","After two male musicians witness a murder, they flee in an all-female band disguised as women.","Violence and mayhem ensue after a man stumbles upon more than two million dollars."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Star Wars?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang","incorrectAnswers":["\"Man! I Feel Like a Woman!\" by Shania Twain","\"You're So Vain\" by Carly Simon","\"Gimme More\" by Britney Spears"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"I said a hip-hop, the hippie the hippie / To the hip, hip hop you don't stop / Rock it to the bang bang boogie / Say up jump the boogie to the rhythm of the boogie, the beat...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Brigadoon","incorrectAnswers":["Ness","Langard","Brenkilly"],"question":"What mythical Scottish town appears for one day every 100 years?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","India","Spain"],"question":"Although the Poodle is widely associated with France, in which country is it believed to have originated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Anthracite","incorrectAnswers":["Bituminous","Lignite","Peat"],"question":"Which of these is a hard variety of coal known for burning with little flame or smoke?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Merlin","incorrectAnswers":["Gandalf","Dumbledore","Morgoth"],"question":"What is the name of the wizard in the legends of King Arthur?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"St. Francis","incorrectAnswers":["St. Peter","St. Paul","St. Augustine"],"question":"Who was born in Assisi in 1181 and later became a missionary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"The iconic album 'Space Oddity' was released by which musician?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Tennis","Track and field","Gymnastics"],"question":"With which sport is Abebe Bikila associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pharaoh","incorrectAnswers":["King Herod","Pontius Pilate","Caesar Augustus"],"question":"In the biblical story of Exodus, who tells Moses 'I know not the Lord, neither will I let Israel go'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Marshall McLuhan","incorrectAnswers":["Noam Chomsky","Edward Snowden","Glenn Greenwald"],"question":"Which pioneering pop-media theorist, born in Edmonton, Alberta, coined the phrase 'The medium is the message'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"James Cook","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Armstrong","Francisco Pizarro","Vasco da Gama"],"question":"Which explorer was killed on the Hawaiian Islands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"San Francisco Bay","incorrectAnswers":["Monterey Bay","Santa Monica Bay","San Diego Bay"],"question":"What bay is connected to the Pacific Ocean by the three-mile-long Golden Gate Strait?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Have it your way","incorrectAnswers":["A glass and a half in every half pound","Finger lickin' good","Snap! Crackle! Pop!"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Burger King?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pointillism","incorrectAnswers":["Post Impressionism","Fauvism","Primitivism"],"question":"The painting \"A Sunday Afternoon on the Island of La Grande Jatte\" by Georges Seurat is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Charles Manson","incorrectAnswers":["Ed Gein","Ted Bundy","Jim Jones"],"question":"Who was the man convicted of masterminding the 1969 LaBianca-Tate murders?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Adventure of the Speckled Band'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Praia","incorrectAnswers":["Santo Domingo","Doha","Saint George's"],"question":"What is the capital city of Cabo Verde?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mariah Carey","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer released the album 'Music Box'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["Colombia","Peru","Chile"],"question":"The Orinoco delta is located in which South American country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Ribbon pasta","Stuffed pasta","Shaped pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is bucatini?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Reservoir Dogs","incorrectAnswers":["Saving Private Ryan","The Green Mile","Gran Torino"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'When a heist goes wrong, the surviving criminals suspect that one of them is a police informant.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Honduras","incorrectAnswers":["Laos","Tanzania","Brunei"],"question":"Tegucigalpa is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},